# **Zunnurain Badar**

Ratta Sharif, P/O Kallar Kahar, Chakwal, Pakistan 48800 +92 333 5934448 zunnurainbadar@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/zunnurainbadar

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Looking for full-time work as a Backend Engineer.

## PERSONAL STATEMENT

I have worked in the technology industry for more than six years and have experience in a variety of roles, including software development, full-stack development, big data, deployment, and management. I have primarily worked in startup environments where I have taken on multiple responsibilities and tackled various technologies, from leading teams to being a versatile team player. Instead of focusing on specific tools or technologies, I prioritize my problem-solving skills. Initially, my career focused on Node.js backend development and database designing and development, but I have continued to learn and expand my skillset with new technologies.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Nodejs
- Nestis
- Go
- Python
- MongoDB
- PostgeSQL
- Clickhouse
- AWS
- Docker
- Kubernetes

## **PERSONAL SKILLS**

#### Management

- Three years' successful experience as team Lead
- Hired and trained staff
- Project Planning & Budgeting.

## Initiative

- Set up new software systems for HR management.
- Changed roster system to reduce costs of staffing

## Communication

- Replied to and solved client enquiries
- Coached team on customer service and problem solving techniques
- Presented monthly statistics to board meetings

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### **lotaScale**

Islamabad 2022-Present

## **Senior Software Engineer**

- Designing and implementing Nodejs REST APIs for a SAAS-based solution.
- Writing and Managing Scripts in Golang and Python.
- Designing and managing the structure and queries of database solutions using Clickhouse, MongoDB and PostgreSQL.
- Debugging, bug fixing, and optimizing code to ensure high performance and reliability.
- Participating in code reviews and contributing to the development of new features and enhancements.

#### **TechAvenue**

Islamabad 2021-2022

## **Senior Software Engineer**

- Conducting research and development on various databases to determine the most suitable option for our specific use case. Additionally, performing thorough testing to assess the compatibility and effectiveness of each database option.
- Creating, Designing and implementing Node.js REST APIs using Typescript and JavaScript.
- Creating and overseeing the architecture and query implementation of database solutions utilizing Clickhouse, MongoDB, and PostgreSQL.
- Writing and Managing Scripts using Python and Golang.
- Managing streams of data using Apache Kafka.

## Micromerger

Islamabad 2018-2021

## Full Stack Developer & Product Lead

- Creating, Designing and implementing Nestis REST APIs.
- Managing and implementing Front end development using Angular (2+).
- Actively managing and overseeing the DevOps side on the AWS cloud platform.
- Overseeing the management of the entire application infrastructure.
- Developing, designing, and implementing PHP REST APIs utilizing the Codelgniter framework.
- Designing the architecture and writing complex SQL queries using PostgreSQL and BigQuery.
- Creating and overseeing the architecture of a real-time database such as Firebase.
- Receiving and managing data from various channels such as Google Cloud Pub/Sub and MQTT.

# **Hybridlogics**

Rawalpindi 2017-2018

# **Senior Software Engineer**

- Creating, and executing Node.js REST APIs utilizing frameworks such as Express.js, Sails, and Loopback.
- Writing and implementing database queries using MongoDB.
- Receiving and handling data sourced from MQTT and Socket.IO.
- Engaging in close collaboration with the team to nurture a high-velocity and productive development process.

## **QUALIFICATIONS**

International Islamic University,

Islamabad 2013-2017

Islamabad

**Bachelor of Science** 

Computer Science